Hi everyone, welcome to our listening course.
First of all, I would like to introduce myself.
My name is teacher Francois and I will
be your instructor for this course.
In this video, I'm going to give you
an introduction to our listening course.
In this IELTS listening advanced course, we will
learn about the common question types in the
IELTS listening test and develop effective strategies to
tackle each one of them.
This includes identifying and paraphrasing keywords, predicting answers,
identifying distractors, and managing your attention across different
speakers and topics.
Develop your listening comprehension skills, including important steps
before the recording starts, while listening and after
completing all the listening questions.
You will not only focus on what to
listen for, but how to listen effectively.
Finally, boost your confidence and exam readiness through
a lot of practice.
You will practice these skills through examples, exercises, and systematic practice tests.
By the end of this course, you will
have completed almost a hundred exercises focusing on
specific question types, ensuring you're fully prepared for
test day.
Now, let's explore the structure of our lessons.
Our lesson will include the following types of section and activity.
First, the review section provides you with information
about the format, key features, and requirements of the question types.
Understanding these fundamentals about a question type will
help us develop good strategies to answer them.
The focus section is where you will learn
about the exact steps and strategies to tackle
each question type.
This section includes a video that walks you
through how each step is implemented for a
sample exercise.
For almost all question types, the basic steps
include reading the requirements and questions, identifying keywords
and paraphrasing, predicting the information that you will
need to listen for, listening and answering the
questions, and finally, checking your answers.
In the focus sections, there will be pop-up exercises for you to apply
these pre-listening steps to the sample exercise.
In many lessons, there will be extra activities
that focus on vocabulary building and avoiding common
mistakes to enhance your listening skills.
This will be included in the enhance your
listening skills sections, which introduces advanced techniques and
suggestions that help you improve your score.
Here, we'll work on skills like tracking multiple
speakers' opinions or dealing with complex distractors.
Finally, in the practice section, you will apply what
you have learned and improve your skills
to exercises.
After each lesson, there will also be a test practice
that helps you practice that question type further.
And throughout the course, there will be three
progress tests to examine how much you have improved.
In our next video, we look at the IELTS Listening Test format in detail
how it is scored, and an overview of which question
types will be covered in this course.
Remember, consistent practice and active engagement with materials
are key to your success.
Let's begin this journey together.